Harry Roskolenko Papers
Harry Roskolenko Papers
- Correspondence-subject files
  - Nisbet, Ulric, 1955 (Box 8)
  - Norman, Dorothy, 1938; 1939 (Box 8)
  - North African Shipping Company, See Hellenic Mediterranean Lines Co. Ltd.
  - Northern Review, 1950-1951; undated (Box 8)
  - W. W. Norton & Company, Inc., 1936; 1937,; 1953 (Box 8)
  - Now, See Woodcock, George
  - Nugget, 1956; 1962-1963 (Box 8)
  - Nussbaum, Louis Frederic, 1950 (Box 8)
  - O, 1 folder (Box 8)
  - O'Dwyer, Joseph, 1944 (Box 8)
  - Okamura, Kazuko, 1947-1950 (Box 8)
  - Outposts, See Sergeant, Howard
  - Oxford University Press, Inc., 1950 (Box 8)
  - Ozick, Cynthia, 1972 (Box 8)
  - P, 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Padell, 1954 (Box 8)
  - Palmer, John E., See The Sewanee Review
  - Pan American World Airways System, 1959-1962 (Box 8)
  - Pastore, Arthur, 1958-1968 (Box 8)
  - Patkin, Michael, 1947; 1958 (Box 8)
  - Penkower, Monty Noam, 1967 (Box 8)
  - Perfect Circle Corporation, 1964 (Box 8)
  - Piaggio & C., 1956-1959 (Box 8)
  - Pierce, Lorne, See Ryerson Press
  - Pinsker, Sanford, 1971-1972 (Box 8)
  - Plain Talk, See Levine, Isaac Don
  - Playboy, 1955; 1963,; 1965 (Box 8)
  - Plenn, Abel, 1934 (Box 8)
  - Plotkin, Harry, See Plotkin, Irving H.
  - Plotkin, Irving H., 1942 (Box 8)
  - Podhoretz, Norman, 1972 (Box 9)
  - Poetry (Chicago), 1934-1943; 1950-1959,; 1967 (Box 9)
  - Poetry London - New York, 1956-1957 (Box 9)
  - Popular Library, Inc., 1954 (Box 9)
  - Poulton, Clive, 1960-1962 (Box 9)
  - Prairie Schooner, 1957-1964 (Box 9)
  - Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1965-1971 (Box 9)
  - Press of James A. Decker, See Decker, Dorothy, Decker, James A., Glauber, Robert H., Tax, Ervin
  - Preston, John Hyde, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Q (Box 9)
  - Qantas, 1969-1971 (Box 9)
  - Quadrangle Books, Inc., See Geltman, Emanuel
  - Quadrant, 1972-1973; undated (Box 9)
  - Quadrant, Nov./Dec. 1972 (Box 9)
  - Quarterly Review of Literature, 1950-1955 (Box 9)
  - Quelquejeu, Camilo, 1959 (Box 9)
  - Quinn, Kerker, See Accent
  - R, 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Rago, Henry, 1955-1959 (Box 9)
  - Rahv, Philip, 1944 (Box 9)
  - Raiziss, Sonia, 1956; 1963,; 1971 (Box 9)
  - Rakosi, Carl, 1972 (Box 9)
  - Random House, Inc., 1945; 1955-1960 (Box 9)
  - Read, Herbert, 1952 (Box 9)
  - Reed, John, See Reed & Harris Publishers
  - Reed & Harris Publishers, 1943-1946; 1956,; undated; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Regency Books, 1962-1964 (Box 9)
  - Rexroth, Kenneth, 1945-1952; 1958,; undated (Box 9)
  - Rexroth, Marie, 1946; 1957,; 1964-1970 (Box 9)
  - Rhys, Keidrych, See Wales
  - Ribalow, Harold U., 1949-1953 (Box 9)
  - Richter, Harvena, 1955-1967 (Box 9)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton, 1955 (Box 9)
  - Rodgers, William, 1958 (Box 9)
  - Rodman, Selden, 1941-1942 (Box 9)
  - Barry Rogliano & Cie, See Hellenic Mediterranean Lines Co. Ltd.
  - Rootes Motors, Inc., 1955-1960; undated; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Rosenberg, Harold, 1942-1943; 1965,; undated (Box 10)
  - Rosenthal, Raymond, 1942-1944 (Box 10)
  - Rosset, Barney, 1958 (Box 10)
  - Rosten, Norman, ca.1953; 1967 (Box 10)
  - Rothe, Friede, 1936-1940 (Box 10)
  - Rovere, Richard H., 1941-1945 (Box 10)
  - Ruben, Philip, 1959 (Box 10)
  - Rundle, Keith, 1946 (Box 10)
  - Russell & Volkening, Inc., 1962-1963; undated (Box 10)
  - Ryerson Press, 1949-1950 (Box 10)
  - S, 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Saini, R. P., 1956-1957 (Box 10)
  - Sandburg, Carl, 1953 (Box 10)
  - Savage, Derek S., 1939 (Box 10)
  - Eugene F. Saxton Memorial Trust, 1966 (Box 10)
  - Schiller, Elizabeth P., 1958 (Box 10)
  - Schneider, Isidor, 1935-1936 (Box 10)
  - Schultz, Henry W., 1936 (Box 10)
  - Schwartz, Selwyn S., ca.1940; ca.1948-1959,; 1968,; undated; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Schwarz, Freimut, 1950 (Box 10)
  - Scott, Winfield Townley, 1935-1941 (Box 10)
  - Selective Service System, 1941-1942 (Box 10)
  - Selley, Stanley, See Modern Motoring and Travel
  - Sergeant, Howard, 1950 (Box 10)
  - The Sewanee Review, 1949 (Box 10)
  - Shapiro, Evalyn, ca.1953 (Box 10)
  - Shapiro, Harvey, 1966 (Box 10)
  - Shapiro, Karl Jay, 1944; ca.1945-1960,; undated (Box 10)
  - Sherman, George, 1940-1941 (Box 10)
  - Shestack, Mel, 1962-1965 (Box 10)
  - Simbolica, ca.1940; 1949,; 1968 (Box 10)
  - Simcoe, Ben, 1960-1963 (Box 10)
  - Simon and Schuster, Inc., 1958-1959 (Box 10)
  - Simpson, Kenneth, 1939 (Box 10)
  - Smiley, Edwin B. W., 1939 (Box 10)
  - Smoke, See DeJong, David C.
  - Socialist Workers Party, 1937-1940; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Sports Illustrated, 1956-1959 (Box 11)
  - Srisubramaniam, T., undated (Box 11)
  - Ssu-Tu, Chiao, 1950 (Box 11)
  - Stein, Irwin, 1963 (Box 11)
  - Stein and Day Publishers, 1963-1964 (Box 11)
  - Stelling, William, 1967-1969 (Box 11)
  - Stettner, Irving, 1956 (Box 11)
  - Stevens, Peter, 1972 (Box 11)
  - Stivens, Dal, 1950 (Box 11)
  - Stock, Irvin, 1972 (Box 11)
  - Stover, B. M., 1939 (Box 11)
  - Straus, Roger W., 1947 (Box 11)
  - Stuart, Lyle, 1959; 1964 (Box 11)
  - Stuhlmann, Gunther, 1968-1970 (Box 11)
  - Sudler & Hennessey, 1959 (Box 11)
  - Sussman, Leonard R., 1972 (Box 11)
  - Sutherland, John, See Northern Review
  - Swallow, Alan, 1950; 1951 (Box 11)
  - Swirsky, Martin, 1943; 1944 (Box 11)
  - Symmes, Robert E., 1940 (Box 11)
  - Symons, Julian, 1939 (Box 11)
  - Szenes, Emery, 1943-1944 (Box 11)
  - T, 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Tambimuttu, 1956-1957 (Box 11)
  - Tanner, Louise, 1969-1971 (Box 11)
  - Tax, Ervin, 1949-1950 (Box 11)
  - Thompson, Malvina, 1939 (Box 11)
  - Thurston, Jarvis A., 1951 (Box 11)
  - Tooker, Dan, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Trager, Frank N., 1972 (Box 11)
  - Transworld Feature Syndicate, Inc., 1956-1959 (Box 11)
  - Treece, Henry, 1939-1966; undated; 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Trilling, Diana, 1972 (Box 11)
  - True, 1957 (Box 11)
  - Tsuboi, Shigeji, 1948 (Box 11)
  - Turnbull, Clive, 1969; 1970 (Box 11)
  - Twayne Publishers, Inc., 1950 (Box 11)
  - Twice a Year, See Norman, Dorothy
  - Tyler, Parker, 1938-1940; undated (Box 11)
  - U, 1 folder (Box 11)
  - U.S. Department of State, 1950-1955; undated (Box 11)
  - U.S. Works Progress Administration, 1937 (Box 11)
  - Upward, See Decker, James A.
  - V, 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Vacuum Oil Company, 1956 (Box 11)
  - Van Starrex, Al, 1956; undated (Box 11)
  - Verney, Kay, 1959 (Box 11)
  - Veterans Administration, 1946-1951 (Box 11)
  - Viereck, Peter, 1972 (Box 11)
  - View, See Decker, James A., Ford, Charles Henri
  - Village Press, See Decker, James A.
  - Villon Press, 1952-1956 (Box 11)
  - Vinal, Harold, ca.1937-1963; undated (Box 11)
  - Voice of America, See U.S. Department of State
  - Voices, See Vinal, Harold
  - Volitant Publishing Corp., 1955-1959 (Box 11)
  - W, 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Waite, Marjorie Peabody, ca.1940 (Box 11)
  - Wakita, Kazu, 1949 (Box 11)
  - Wald, Jerry, 1960-1961; undated (Box 11)
  - Wales, 1939 (Box 11)
  - Ward Manufacturing, Inc., 1959 (Box 11)
  - Wasserman, Dale, 1963 (Box 11)
  - Weider Publications, Inc., 1953-1954; undated (Box 12)
  - Weinstock, Sylvia, 1972 (Box 12)
  - Weiss, David, 1957 (Box 12)
  - Weiss, Neil, 1953 (Box 12)
  - Weiss, Stymean, ca.1953 (Box 12)
  - Weiss, Theodore, See Quarterly Review of Literature
  - Western Printing and Lithography Co., 1954-1955 (Box 12)
  - Wheeler, Thomas, 1972; undated (Box 12)
  - Wheelwright, John, 1937-1939 (Box 12)
  - White, Emil, ca.1945 (Box 12)
  - Wigutow, Charles, 1937; 1956 (Box 12)
  - Williams, Mary, ca.1943; undated (Box 12)
  - Winchell, Walter, 1946 (Box 12)
  - Winslow, Kathryn, 1950 (Box 12)
  - Wolf, Simon, 1956-1959 (Box 12)
  - Wolk, Shulamith Raskin, 1940-1944; 1950,; undated (Box 12)
  - Woodcock, George, 1945-1951 (Box 12)
  - Wyllis Motors, Inc., 1961 (Box 12)
  - Wyss, Robert, 1962 (Box 12)
  - Y, 1 folder (Box 12)
  - Yaddo, See Ames, Elizabeth
  - Young, Violet, 1945-1946 (Box 12)
  - Z, 1 folder (Box 12)
  - Zabel, Morton Dauwen, 1934-1937 (Box 12)
  - Zabriskie, Tanya, 1959-1963; ca.1948 (Box 12)
  - Zao, Wou-Ki, 1950; 1952,; undated (Box 12)
  - Zentner, David, 1955-1964 (Box 12)
  - Zero, See Benveniste, Albert
  - Unidentified (Box 12)
- Writings
  - Book manuscripts (unpublished)
    - "The Core and the Surface", ms. draft [A]; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - "The Core and the Surface", ms. draft [B]; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - "The Core and the Surface", ms. draft [C]; 4 folders (Box 13)
    - "The Core and the Surface", ms. draft [D]; 3 folders (Box 13)
    - "The Core and the Surface", ms. draft [E] (Box 13)
    - "The Core and the Surface", ms. draft [F]; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - "Incest in America", 9 reel-to-reel tapes in 2 folders (Oversize 1)
    - "The Italian Riviera After Dark" / Ross, Colin (pseud.), ms. draft; 3 folders (Box 14)
    - "The Italian Riviera After Dark", ms. draft - "new material" (Box 14)
    - "The Italian Riviera After Dark", ms. draft - "second carbon of revisions" (Box 14)
    - "The Italian Riviera After Dark", ms. draft - "deleted material" (Box 14)
    - "My Father's Time", ms. draft [A] (Box 14)
    - "My Father's Time", ms. draft [B] (Box 14)
    - "My Father's Time", ms. draft [C] (Box 14)
    - "Samoan Idyll", ms. draft - "a brief outline of the novel" (Box 14)
    - "Samoan Idyll", ms. draft [A]; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - "Samoan Idyll", ms. draft [B] (Box 14)
    - "Samoan Idyll", ms. draft - "suggestions for revision" (Box 14)
    - "Sex & the Food You Eat", 6 reel-to-reel tapes (Oversize 1)
    - "Sex & the Food You Eat", transcription from tapes; 2 folders (Box 15)
    - "Sex & the Food You Eat", ms. draft; 2 folders (Box 15)
    - "View from the Couch", ms. draft; 8 folders (Box 15)
  - Books
    - Baedeker of a Batchelor (working title: "Out of Myself and My Country I Go"), ms. draft [A]; 5 folders (Box 16)
    - Baedeker of a Batchelor (working title: "Out of Myself and My Country I Go"), ms. draft [B]; 4 folders (Box 16)
    - Baedeker of a Batchelor, ms. draft [C]; 3 folders (Box 16)
    - Baedeker of a Batchelor (working title: "Exile--to a Journey"), ms. draft [D]; 4 folders (Box 16)
    - Baedeker of a Batchelor, front matter - ms. draft (Box 17)
    - Baedeker of a Batchelor, dust jacket - ms. draft (Box 17)
    - Baedeker of a Batchelor, press release - ms. draft (Box 17)
    - Baedeker of a Batchelor, production records - dust jacket (Box 17)
    - Baedeker of a Batchelor, production records - galleys (Box 17)
    - Baedeker of a Batchelor, 1952; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Black Is a Man, outline (Box 17)
    - Black Is a Man, ms. draft; 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Black Is a Man, ms. draft - "inserts" (Box 17)
    - Black Is a Man, dust jacket - ms. draft (Box 17)
    - Black Is a Man, production records - dust jacket (Box 17)
    - Black Is a Man, production records - galleys (Box 17)
    - Black Is a Man, reviews (Box 17)
    - Bombay After Dark / Ross, Allen V. (pseud.), outline (Box 17)
    - Bombay After Dark, ms. draft [A]; 3 folders (Box 17)
    - Bombay After Dark, ms. draft [B]; 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Bombay After Dark, ms. draft [C]; 3 folders (Box 18)
    - Bombay After Dark, ms. draft [D]; 3 folders (Box 18)
    - Bombay After Dark, 1966 (Box 18)
    - The Exiles' Anthology, 1940; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - The French Riviera After Dark / Ballard, Jean de (pseud.), ms. draft; 3 folders (Box 18)
    - The French Riviera After Dark, manuscript (carbon); 5 folders (Box 18)
    - I Went into the Country, dust jacket - ms. draft (Box 19)
    - I Went into the Country, publicity, reviews (Box 19)
    - I Went into the Country, 1941; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Ladies in the Rough / Niloc, Paul (pseud.), undated; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Lan-Lan, research material (Box 19)
    - Lan-Lan, 1962; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - The Mistress / Niloc, Paul (pseud.), 1954; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to (Box 19)
    - New York After Dark / Ross, Colin (pseud.), outline (Box 19)
    - New York After Dark, ms. draft [A]; 2 folders (Box 19)
    - New York After Dark, ms. draft [B]; 3 folders (Box 19)
    - New York After Dark, ms. draft [C]; 3 folders (Box 19)
    - New York After Dark, 1966 (Box 19)
    - Notes from a Journey, ms. draft (Box 19)
    - Notes from a Journey, illustration by Sidney Nolan (reproduction) (Box 19)
    - Notes from a Journey, reviews (Box 19)
    - Notes from a Journey, 1948; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Paris After Dark / Ballard, Jean de (pseud.), outline (Box 19)
    - Paris After Dark, ms. draft [A] (Box 19)
    - Paris After Dark, ms. draft [B]; 4 folders (Box 20)
    - Paris After Dark, ms. draft [C]; 3 folders (Box 20)
    - Paris After Dark, ms. draft (misc. pp.) (Box 20)
    - Paris After Dark, 1966 (Box 20)
    - Paris Poems, ms. draft [A] (Box 20)
    - Paris Poems, ms. draft [B] (Box 20)
    - Paris Poems, publicity (Box 20)
    - Paris Poems, reviews (Box 20)
    - Poet on a Scooter, research material/memorabilia; 3 folders of 6 (Box 20)
    - Poet on a Scooter, research material/memorabilia; 3 folders of 6 (Box 21)
    - Poet on a Scooter, ms. draft [A]; 4 folders (Box 21)
    - Poet on a Scooter, ms. draft [B]; 3 folders (Box 21)
    - Poet on a Scooter, dust jacket - ms. draft (Box 21)
    - Poet on a Scooter, publicity, reviews (Box 21)
    - Poet on a Scooter, 1958; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - The Private Life of Eleanor / Coss, Rollin (pseud.), 1959; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - The Rape of the Heart / Crozier, H. R. (pseud.) (working title: "Japanese novel"), ms. draft [A]; 2 folders (Box 22)
    - The Rape of the Heart (working titles: "Death in the Paddies," "The Assassins"), ms. draft [B] (Box 22)
    - The Rape of the Heart (working title: "The Terrorized"), ms. draft [C] (Box 22)
    - The Rape of the Heart (working title: "The Terrorized"), ms. draft [D]; 3 folders (Box 22)
    - The Rape of the Heart, ms. draft [E]; 4 folders (Box 22)
    - The Rape of the Heart, production records - galleys - Chapter 1 (Box 22)
    - The Rape of the Heart, 1953; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Season of Love / Ross, Colin (pseud.), ms. draft; 2 folders (Box 22)
    - A Second Summary, ms. draft [A] (Box 23)
    - A Second Summary, ms. draft [B] (Box 23)
    - A Second Summary, Introduction by M. Harris - ms. draft, galley (corrected) (Box 23)
    - A Second Summary, Introduction by H. Treece - ms. draft (Box 23)
    - A Second Summary, publicity, reviews (Box 23)
    - Sequence on Violence, reviews (Box 23)
    - Sequence on Violence, 1938; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - The Terrorized, research material; See also Books: Lan-Lan - research material (Box 23)
    - The Terrorized, notes (Box 23)
    - The Terrorized, ms. draft [A]; 4 folders (Box 23)
    - The Terrorized, ms. draft [B]; 6 folders (Box 23, 24)
    - The Terrorized, ms. draft [C]; 7 folders (Box 24)
    - The Terrorized, additions, corrections (Box 24)
    - The Terrorized, setting copy; 4 folders (Box 24, 25)
    - The Terrorized, production records - galleys; 3 folders (Box 25)
    - The Terrorized, production records - galleys -"errors, corrections, changes" (Box 25)
    - The Terrorized, production records - galleys - front matter (Box 25)
    - The Terrorized, production records - plate proof (confirmation proof) (Box 25)
    - The Terrorized, production records - plate proof (master set) (Box 25)
    - The Terrorized, 1967; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - The Time That Was Then, research material (Box 26)
    - The Time That Was Then, notes (Box 26)
    - The Time That Was Then, transcription of tapes; 3 folders (Box 26)
    - The Time That Was Then, ms. draft (Box 26)
    - The Time That Was Then, ms. draft, revised (Box 26)
    - The Time That Was Then, setting copy; 3 folders (Box 26)
    - The Time That Was Then, production records - galleys; 2 folders (Box 26)
    - To Take a Wife, dust jacket (Box 27)
    - The Velvet Underground / Leigh, Michael (pseud.), 1963; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - The Velvet Underground Revisited / Leigh, Michael (pseud.), ms. draft [A]; 3 folders (Box 27)
    - The Velvet Underground Revisited, ms. draft [B]; 2 folders (Box 27)
    - The Velvet Underground Revisited, ms. draft [C]; 2 folders (Box 27)
    - The Velvet Underground Revisited, setting copy; 3 folders (Box 27)
    - The Velvet Underground Revisited, 1968 (Box 27)
    - When I Was Last on Cherry Street, notes, research material (Box 28)
    - When I Was Last on Cherry Street, ms. draft [A]; 3 folders (Box 28)
    - When I Was Last on Cherry Street, ms. draft [B]; 2 folders (Box 28)
    - When I Was Last on Cherry Street, ms. draft [C]; 3 folders (Box 28)
    - When I Was Last on Cherry Street, ms. draft [D]; 2 folders (Box 28)
    - When I Was Last on Cherry Street, front matter - ms. draft (Box 28)
    - When I Was Last on Cherry Street, dust jacket - ms. draft (Box 28)
    - When I Was Last on Cherry Street, manuscript, copyedited; 3 folders (Box 29)
    - When I Was Last on Cherry Street, deletions, revisions (Box 29)
    - When I Was Last on Cherry Street, inserts (Box 29)
    - When I Was Last on Cherry Street, production records -page proof (Box 29)
    - When I Was Last on Cherry Street, reviews (Box 29)
    - When I Was Last on Cherry Street, 1965; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - White Man Go!, proposals (Box 29)
    - White Man Go!, notebooks (10) (Box 29)
    - White Man Go!, memorabilia - advanced publicity for trip (Box 29)
    - White Man Go!, memorabilia (miscellaneous) (Box 29)
    - White Man Go!, photographs (Box 29)
    - White Man Go!, ms. draft; 2 folders (Box 29)
    - White Man Go!, 1962; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
  - Essays
    - "African Adventure", ms. draft (Box 39)
    - "Albert Namatjira: a Modernist Among the Boomerang People", ms. draft, photographs (Box 30)
    - "America Goes Adventuring", ms. drafts (Box 39)
    - "An American Clown in Paris", ms. draft (Box 39)
    - "An American Jew in Egypt", ms. drafts (Box 30)
    - "An American Jew in Egypt" - American Judaism, Apr. 1961 (Box 30)
    - "American Letter" - Angry Penguins, Dec. 1945 (Box 30)
    - "American Letter", review (Box 30)
    - "American Poets", ms. draft (Box 39)
    - "'arf 'n' 'arf 'n' 'istory" (working titles: "Some Famous English Pubs," "Where Englishmen Let Down Their Hair"), ms. drafts (Box 30)
    - "'arf 'n' 'arf 'n' 'istory" - Escapade, July 1956 (Box 30)
    - "Around the World on a Scooter" - New York Herald Tribune, undated (Box 30)
    - "Attitudes and Services to be Rendered" - Transformation Two / S. Schimanski, H. Treece, ed., 1944; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - "Australia and the Aborigines" - Modern Review, Oct. 1947 (Box 30)
    - "Australia: Facts, Figures and Fancies", ms. draft (Box 30)
    - "Australian Literary Report" - The New Leader, Feb. 15, 1947 (Box 30)
    - "The Australian Writer", ms. draft (Box 30)
    - "Be Your Own Cop -- But", ms. drafts (Box 39)
    - "Better Read than Dead?" (working title: "Proletarian Literature - and Black Nationalism Agit-Prop"), ms. drafts (Box 30)
    - "Better Read than Dead?" - Books, Sept. 1968 (Box 30)
    - "Big Game Hunting with Bambi" - Modern Motoring and Travel, Feb. 1960 (Box 30)
    - "Binh Xuyen -- the Pirates of Saigon", ms. draft (Box 39)
    - "Blood and Politics -- New Guinea Style", ms. drafts (Box 39)
    - "The Boomerang People--the Aborigines of Australia", ms. draft (Box 30)
    - "Bum-hemians in Paris", ms. draft (Box 39)
    - "The Cant in Pound's Cantos" (working title: "Pound's Cantos"), ms. draft (Box 30)
    - "The Cant in Pound's Cantos" - Congress Weekly, Apr. 11, 1949 (Box 30)
    - "The Cant in Pound's Cantos", reviews (Box 30)
    - "Celine: Literary Anti-Semite" (working title: "Celine in Retrospect"), ms. draft (Box 30)
    - "Celine: Literary Anti-Semite" - Congress Weekly, Jan. 30, 1950 (Box 30)
    - "The Celine Mish-mash", research material (Box 30)
    - "The Celine Mish-mash", ms. draft (Box 30)
    - "The Celine Mish-mash" - Congress Weekly, Mar. 20, 1950 (Box 30)
    - "China: the Necessity for Action", ms. draft (Box 30)
    - "China: the Necessity for Action" - Plain Talk, Jan. 1949 (Box 30)
    - "Conversations with Carl Sandburg" - The Chicago Jewish Forum, Spring 1953 (Box 30)
    - "Death in the Desert", notes and research material (Box 39)
    - "Death in the Desert", ms. drafts (Box 39)
    - "Don't Fill 'er Up", ms. drafts (Box 39)
    - "Dos Passos' Philosophy" - Angry Penguins Broadsheet, no. 4, 1946 (Box 30)
    - "Enormous War Profits by Shipping Companies" / Goode, Elizabeth (pseud.) - Tomorrow, undated (Box 30)
    - "Enveloping Decay", ms. draft (Box 39)
    - "Fireman's Holiday in Dolenske Toplice", ms. drafts (Box 39)
    - "Fireworks in the Far East" - The New Leader, May 31, 1947 (Box 30)
    - "Five American Jewish Poets" - The Chicago Jewish Forum, v. 12, no. 1 (Box 30)
    - "From Kure to Hiroshima" - The Canadian Forum, July 1947 (Box 30)
    - "General MacArthur and Some of His Critics", ms. draft (Box 39)
    - "Germany Today", ms. draft (Box 30)
    - "Germany Today" - Congress Weekly, Oct. 9, 1950 (Box 30)
    - "Hardship Takes No Holiday in Japan" - Digest of World Reading, Apr. 1947 (Box 30)
    - "Harrison Kerr", ms. draft (Box 39)
    - "Hemingway's Great Mountain ... Kilimanjaro", ms. draft (Box 30)
    - "Hemingway's Great Mountain ... Kilimanjaro" - Modern Motoring and Travel, Jan. 1960 (Box 30)
    - "Hungry Hunters with Harpoons" - Digest of World Reading, May 1947 (Box 30)
    - "Husky They Call It" (working title: "Nile Journey"), ms. draft (Box 30)
    - "Husky They Call It" - Car Life, undated (Box 30)
    - "In a Turkish Village" - The Diplomat, June 1957 (Box 30)
    - "In a Turkish Village" - The Illustrated Weekly of India, July 14, 1957 (Box 30)
    - "Indelicacy and Shock" (working title: "Notes for an article on E. E. Cummings"), ms. draft (Box 30)
    - "Indelicacy and Shock" - Congress Weekly, Aug. 20, 1951 (Box 30)
    - "Interim Flight", ms. drafts (Box 39)
    - "Jean Forand, French Worker", ms. drafts (Box 39)
    - "Jewish Artists in Paris", ms. drafts (Box 30)
    - "Jewish Intellectuals in Paris" (working title: "In Transit Through Paris"), ms. draft (Box 30)
    - "Jewish Intellectuals in Paris" - The Chicago Jewish Forum, Fall 1950 (Box 30)
    - "John Wheelwright" - Fantasy, 1941 (Box 30)
    - "Journey into History" (working title: "I Am Grass--Let Me Work!"), ms. drafts (Box 30)
    - "Journey into History" - Digest of World Reading, Jan. 1947 (Box 30)
    - "Kaleidoscope on a Scooter", ms. drafts (Box 30)
    - "Kaleidoscope on a Scooter" - The Fiji Times, Feb. 2, 1957 (Box 30)
    - "Kaleidoscope on a Scooter" - The Illustrated Weekly of India, May 12, 1957 (Box 30)
    - "Kenya -- the Next Round", ms. draft (Box 39)
    - "Kenya Safari" - The Jobber Journal, Winter 1963 (Box 30)
    - "Letter from Australia" (working title: "Literary Letter from Australia"), ms. drafts (Box 39)
    - "Letter from Australia" - The New York Times Book Review, Oct. 26, 1969 (Box 39)
    - "A Letter from Australia", production records - page proof (Box 30)
    - "A Letter from Australia" - Poetry, undated (Box 30)
    - "Letter from Hong Kong" - Focus, May 1947 (Box 30)
    - "Letter from Japan", undated; printed material (Box 30)
    - "Letter from Japan" (working title: "The Commerce of Expediency"), ms. draft (Box 30)
    - "Letter from Japan" - Modern Review, July 1947 (Box 30)